<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Systems Thinking on The Nukemblog</title><link>https://blog.nukemberg.com/tags/systems-thinking/</link><description>Recent content in Systems Thinking on The Nukemblog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 23:42:41 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nukemberg.com/tags/systems-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Scaling of Dichotomies</title><link>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/the-scaling-of-dichotomies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 23:42:41 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/the-scaling-of-dichotomies/</guid><description>When I was a small boy I used to spend hours playing the &amp;ldquo;war&amp;rdquo; card game. The thing about this game is, it&amp;rsquo;s totally predictable and deterministic - each player gets a shuffled half of the deck and cards are extracted one by one in order. No chance or skill involved whatsoever and the result is completely determined by the pack you were dealt - we could just as well determine the winner by a coin toss.</description></item><item><title>Fooled by Randomness</title><link>https://blog.nukemberg.com/book/fooled-by-randomness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 17:28:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nukemberg.com/book/fooled-by-randomness/</guid><description/></item><item><title>If all you have is MS Project, everything looks like a time estimate</title><link>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/if-all-you-have-is-ms-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 10:24:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/if-all-you-have-is-ms-project/</guid><description>One of the things that struck me the most when observing managers at work, and in particular newly instated managers, is how managers become more and more out of touch with the realities of work. There&amp;rsquo;s actually a lot of research on that from quite a bit of different perspectives. Safety research for example has interesting things to say about &amp;ldquo;work as imagined&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;work as done&amp;rdquo;. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen over night of course, but rather a slow process - and I found it has a lot to do with the shift from doing and experiencing to planning and monitoring.</description></item><item><title>Plans are valuable, but planning is invaluable</title><link>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/plans-are-valuable-planning-is-invaluable/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 05:05:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/plans-are-valuable-planning-is-invaluable/</guid><description>In preparing for battle I have always found that plans are useless, but planning is indispensable. Dwight D. Eisenhower What would you give for the ability to predict the future? a lot I presume. Knowing the future (and being free to act on it) can make you rich, successful, almost indestructible. What would you give to know the future with 90% probability of being right? well, if you can participate in the lottery every week 90% pretty much guarantees success, definitely valuable.</description></item><item><title>No, engineers don't suck at time estimates</title><link>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/no-engineers-dont-suck-at-estimates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 21:14:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/no-engineers-dont-suck-at-estimates/</guid><description>No, engineers don&amp;rsquo;t suck at time estimates - and generally speaking humans are better estimators than what most people believe. This seems rather surprising given all we&amp;rsquo;ve heard about the problems of bad time estimations, projects going overboard, etc and of course, your personal experience with software time estimates. But if people are really bad at estimation, how does that fit with our obvious evolutionary need to make quick decisions based on partial data?</description></item><item><title>The Burndown Chart Fallacy</title><link>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/the-burndown-chart-fallacy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 22:34:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/the-burndown-chart-fallacy/</guid><description>Have you ever walked into an office and saw a huge flat screen on the wall displaying a dashboard with pretty graphs, or some other nice visualization showing some important looking numbers? Back when people still frequented offices, many had them. But have you ever wondered, what are they for? No engineer is looking at them, because when you are looking at data you want to interact with the data, zoom, pan or apply some filter.</description></item><item><title>Blame It on the Phones</title><link>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/blame-it-on-the-phones/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 22:50:08 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nukemberg.com/post/blame-it-on-the-phones/</guid><description>Since I&amp;rsquo;ve abandoned Facebook my primary source of tech news has become Twitter and this week my feed is raging with two seemingly unrelated security/privacy incidents: Zoom&amp;rsquo;s zero day and Superhuman&amp;rsquo;s email tracking scandal. I write &amp;ldquo;seemingly&amp;rdquo;, because despite these being two very different companies operating in two different markets (Zoom in video conference calls and Superhuman in emails), building very different products (Zoom is all about jump in, jump out - Superhuman is a workspace) these incidents stem from the same fundamental fault: The telephone experience.</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to General Systems Thinking</title><link>https://blog.nukemberg.com/book/an-introduction-to-general-systems-thinking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 15:02:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nukemberg.com/book/an-introduction-to-general-systems-thinking/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>